Ahmad Hamid Zacky Shebubakar

Address : Jl. Angsana 1 No. 19 Rt 008/05, Pejaten Timur, Jakarta 12510, Indonesia

Phone : +62812 9074 8334 / +62856 8958 111

Email : <u>Hamid.Shebubakar@gmail.com</u>

Personal Statement

A Procurement specialist and Estimator for oil & gas EPC company. As a procurement specialist, I have skills and knowledge in engineering, commercial and project management. I also work to helps Business Development to enter Power Plant Projects by performing strategic analysis to win a project and help to create good relation with the main equipment suppliers.

Education

2005-2010 Institut Teknologi Bandung (ITB)

Bachelor degree in Electrical Engineering with Thesis "Design of tracing camera for virtual class".

Experience

PT. Tripatra Engineers & Constructors (December 2010 - Now)

Business Development (March 2016 - Now)

Job description:

- Analyzed list of potential upcoming EPC projects from Rencana Usaha Penyediaan Tenaga Listrik (RUPTL).
- Analyzed the Instruction To Bid (ITB) and tendering procedure, as well as providing insight & strategy for bids.
- Developed Owner Estimation of the projects
- Maintained good relation with main equipment suppliers
- Planning Strategic Operation & Maintenance with partner
- Developed study and analysis for winning potential of certain type of Main Equipment in Power Projects

<u>Lead Procurement Engineer Act. (Jan 2014 - Now)</u>

Job description:

- Researched potential Vendors & Subcontractors
- Analyzed cost of an equipment for negotiation
- Performed vendor selection based on certain commercial criteria
- Expedited procured item from engineering phase to installation & Commissioning phase
- Locate stock item around the globe to fulfill project schedule
- Assisted finance for Invoicing procedure, i.e. Goods Receipt input and Invoicing accrual
- Assisted document control team to expedite and clear out Vendor Documentation
- Coordinate with logistic and engineering team for Over Dimension Cargo shipment

Project Engineer (June 2012-Now)

Job description:

• Performed interfacing between engineering discipline

- Analyzed all scope of works and create scope of works & supply matrix
- Coordinate with engineering to analyze any potential change order, both technical and commercial aspect
- Coordinate with site team to find solution for problems at installation & commissioning phase

Estimator (March 2011 - Now)

Job description:

- Performed estimation cost for Tendering project
- Sourced new Vendor for specified projects
- Performed estimation price with justification by using experience, database or request vendor for fresh quotation
- Provided inputs to engineering to optimize their design for better pricing

Procurement Engineer (Dec 2010 - Dec 2013)

Job description:

- Sent inquiry to Vendors & Subcontractors
- Performed commercial bid analysis
- Commercial negotiation with Vendors
- Provided database for Estimation Project
- Performed Purchase order and Subcontracting agreement to Vendors

Project Involvement

Business Development for Power Plant

- 1. Riau Peaker- Gas Turbine Power Plant (200 MW)
- 2. Sumbagut Peaker Combine Cycle Gas Turbine (250 MW)
- 3. Package 4&5 Fixed Dual Fuel Power Plant (50 MW)
- 4. Package 7&8 Mobile Dual Fuel Power Plant (50 MW)
- 5. Package-1 20 MW Fixed Power Plant (PLN)
- 6. Nias 25 MW mobile Power Plant (PLN)

Execution of Complex Project (Procurement, Estimation and Project Engineering)

- 1. Exxon Mobil Cepu Limited Banyu Urip EPC-1 Project (USD 1.1 Billion), Bojonegoro, East Java, Indonesia
- 2. JOB Medco-Pertamina Senoro Gas Development Project (USD 650 Million), Senoro, Central Sulawesi, Indonesia
- 3. Indoturbine-Pertamina EP Musi Timur Gas Development Project (USD 60 Million), South Sumatra, Indonesia

Project Execution

- 1. E1-Pertagas South Sumatera NGL Project (USD 250 Million), South Sumatra, Indonesia
- 2. Danagas Zora Gas FEED Project (USD 9 Million), UAE
- 3. Chevron Bangka Top FEED (USD 19 Million), East Kalimantan, Indonesia
- 4. Chevron Asset Integrity FEED Project (USD 9 Million), Riau, Indonesia

Estimation of Complex Project (Estimation & Project Engineering)

1. Chevron Gendalo-Gehem FPU and Subsea (USD 3.4 Billion) East Kalimantan, Indonesia

- 2. Eni Jangkrik FPU(USD 1.1 Billion), East Kalimantan, Indonesia
- 3. BP Tangguh Train-3 expansion project (USD 2.4 Billion), West Papua, Indonesia
- 4. Pertamina EP Jambaran Tiung Biru Project (USD 1 Billion), Bojonegoro, East Java, Indonesia

Project Proposal & Estimation

- 1. Pertamina RFCC Cilacap (USD 800 Million), Cilacap, Central Java, Indonesia
- 2. Bangladesh Sylhet molecular sieve (USD 160 Million), Bangladesh
- 3. Conocophillips Dayung & Grisik De-bottlenecking Gas Plant Proposal (USD 136 Million), South Sumatra, Indonesia
- 4. Conocophillips Sumpal Expansion Project (USD 86 Million), South Sumatra, Indonesia
- 5. PLN PLTG Batanghari (USD 70 Million), Batang Hari, Jambi, Indonesia
- 6. PLN Krakatau Daya Listrik (120 Million) Cilegon, Banten, Indonesia
- 7. Petro Kimia Gresik Petrochemical Proposal (USD 200 Million), Gresik, East Java, Indonesia
- 8. Antam Refining 3 MOP-FeNi (USD 400 Million), Pomalaa, Southeast Sulawesi, Indonesia
- 9. PLN CNG Plant for Peaking Power Generation (USD 40 Million) Sei Gelam, Jambi, Indonesia
- 10. MEDCO Block A Project (USD 600 Million), Aceh, Indonesia
- 11. PUSRI IIB Ammonia Project (USD 400 Million), Palembang, South Sumatra, Indonesia
- 12. Pertamina EP Donggi Matindok Gas Development (USD 140 Million), Central Sulawesi, Indonesia
- 13. Berau Energy Overland Coal (USD 50 Million), East Kalimantan, Indonesia
- 14. PTPN V Palm Oil Plant (USD 40 Million), North Sumatra, Indonesia
- 15. PTPN X Bioethanol Sugar Refinery Plant (USD 80 Million), Kediri, East Java, Indonesia

Skills

- Computing: Microsoft Office, Microsoft Windows, SAP, Linux
- Language: English (oral & written) Bahasa Indonesia (Native Oral & Written)
- Organization:
 - Member of KM (Kabinet Mahasiswa) ITB, economics department (2005-2007)
 - o Minister of Finance of HME (Himpunan Mahasiswa Elektro) ITB (2007-2008)

Reference

Sudarsono

SCM Project Manager Banyu Urip Project SCM Project Manager Tangguh Expansion Project sudarsono@tripatra.com

Raymond N. Rasfuldi

Executive Director for New Business & Business Development raymond.rasfuldi@tripatra.com

Ferdiansyah

SCM Coordinator for Proposal & Estimation f.ferdiansyah@tripatra.com

Demas Seto Ardhiwirawan

Procurement Specialist for Supreme Energy demas-seto@supreme-energy.com

Rudi Agus Hermawan

Project Engineer for Chevron Indonesia RudiHermawan@chevron.com

Disclaimer: Since I am still working with Tripatra, please kindly inform me before contacting one of the referees from Tripatra.